https://www.kmlabs.com/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
Important information about the safeguarding of your information
Safeguarding your personal information
In today's connected world, unauthorized attempts to access information are a reality with which private individuals and companies are confronted on a daily basis. Safeguarding information against such attempts is a considerable challenge.
Data protection is a high priority issue at KMLabs, Inc., and we invest time, energy and money into ensuring that our systems are secure. When you use our web pages and respond to our communications, you entrust us with your personal information. Safeguarding this information is important to us.
Data Protection Notice
Scope
This data protection notice applies to web pages, domains, social media platforms and applications belonging to KMLabs, Inc. (Hereinafter simply referred to as KMLabs.)
In some cases, KMLabs’ web pages also contain links to web pages of third-party, external companies such as distributors to which this data protection and legal notice does not apply.
General Data Protection Standard
KMLabs is a corporation operating on a global scale.
When you visit our web pages, data may be collected which may, in some cases, be of a personal nature. In this notice, we point out what personal information we collect during your visit to our web pages, and how we handle this data.
We consider the protection of your personal information a very serious matter. Our processing of your personal information collected during your visit to our web pages is carried out fully in accordance with the relevant legal stipulations. In addition, our approach to dealing with personal information is based on the EU data protection principles that provide for the greatest possible degree of transparency, observance of the right to choose, access rights, and the transmission and lawful processing of personal information.
Furthermore, KMLabs is permitted to collect and process address and order information for its own marketing purposes. This means, for example, that KMLabs may compare email addresses collected during order processes with Facebook Ireland Limited's email address lists in order to display personalized advertisements to the owner of the address. Facebook Ireland Limited is not permitted, however, to use the email address for any purpose other than comparing it with its address list. Information is sent to third parties for advertising purposes only in cases where it is legally permissible to do so.
Note
You may object to the use, processing, and transfer of your personal information at any time by means of an informal written letter addressed to KMLabs or via email (add link to form). Upon receipt of your objection, we will cease to use, process, and transfer the information in question for any purpose other than carrying out the orders and tasks you have requested; we will also cease to send you advertising and promotional materials.
Gathering, Processing, and Transfer of Personal Information
KMLabs wants to give you as much control as possible over your personal information. Normally, you can access KMLabs web pages without providing any personal information.
However, in certain areas of the KMLabs web pages, you are requested to provide us with personal information in order to help us enhance the site and keep in contact with you. Any personal information you submit is treated as confidential and is saved and processed exclusively within the scope of the relationship between you and KMLabs. Your personal information will not be forwarded, published, or otherwise made available to third parties for marketing purposes.
However, as part of the provision of our services, your information may under certain circumstances be transferred to third parties who we have included in order processing, e.g. business partners or IT service providers. When transferring personal information to these third parties, we restrict ourselves to the information that is necessary for the provision of the service in question and we ensure that this transfer is carried out in compliance with the required data security. KMLabs will only transfer your personal information to third parties that have committed themselves to data protection and to the processing of your information in compliance with the applicable laws.
In addition, KMLabs may be forced by court or official order to reveal your data and associated information. Likewise, we reserve the right to use your information for the assertion of or defense against legal claims.
In the event of a takeover or merger with another company, it may be necessary to disclose or transfer your information to actual or potential buyers. In this case, KMLabs will aspire to the highest possible level of data protection and will comply with the legal stipulations.
Rights of the Data Subject
You are entitled to request information regarding the personal data we process at any time; you may also object to the processing of this information as well as request that the extent to which your personal information is processed be limited, that information be corrected or that information be deleted. Please note that KMLabs may only delete your personal information in the event that no legal stipulations exist that require this information to be stored, or in the event that KMLabs' right to store this information does not take precedence over your right to have it deleted. Please also note that once you have requested to have your information deleted, to have the processing of your information limited, or you have objected to the processing of your information, you may then no longer use KMLabs services, in part or in full, which require the use of your personal information.
If your personal information is being used by KMLabs because you have agreed to have it used, or because it is required for the fulfillment of a contract you have concluded with KMLabs, you may request a copy of the information that you have made available to KMLabs. Please send your request to the email address provided below. Be sure to include which data or processing activities you are requesting information about, in what format you would like to receive this information, and whether the information should be sent to you or another recipient. KMLabs will carefully review your request and inform you of the best way to fulfill it.
You may also request that KMLabs limit the future processing of your personal information in the following cases:
If you claim that the personal information held by KMLabs is incorrect (however, the processing of information in this case will only be limited during the period of time needed by KMLabs to verify the accuracy of the personal information in question);
If there is no legal basis for the processing of your personal information by KMLabs and you request that KMLabs cease processing your information;
If KMLabs no longer needs your personal information, but you claim that KMLabs must store this information so that legal claims can be raised or exercised, or so that the claims of third parties can be defended;
If you object to the processing of your personal information by KMLabs (on the basis of KMLabs' legitimate interest), for the length of time required to verify if KMLabs' interest in processing your personal information takes precedence or if a legal requirement to store the information exists.
[View form]
Personal Information of Children: KMLabs does not intentionally collect or process the information of children under the age of 16, or as required by local laws.
Compliance with Legal Regulations
KMLabs and its products, services and technologies are subject to the export regulations of various countries, including those of the European Union and its member states and those of the United States. You acknowledge that KMLabs is required, per applicable export regulations, trade sanctions, and embargoes, to take measures to prevent companies, organizations, and parties named in sanction party lists from acquiring certain products, technologies, and services through KMLabs web pages or delivery channels controlled by KMLabs. These measures may include the following:
The automated comparison of user registration information described in this notice and other information related to the user's identity with applicable sanction lists;
Regular and repeated comparisons of this information as sanction lists are updated or as the user updates his or her information;
The blocking of access to the services and systems of KMLabs if a user is found in an applicable sanction list;
Establishing contact with the user in the event his or her information is found in a sanction list in order to verify his or her identity.
Furthermore, you acknowledge that information required to carry out activities in accordance with your decision to have your personal information processed and used, or to receive marketing and promotional materials from KMLabs (regardless of whether you have provided your explicit permission or objection to receive marketing and promotional materials) may be stored by KMLabs and its distributor-partners and exchanged between them to the extent this is required by law.
Legitimate Interest of KMLabs
Each of the items listed below presents a case in which KMLabs has a legitimate interest in processing and using your personal information. If you do not agree to having your information processed and used by KMLabs in these ways, you may object to these processing activities.
View form
Surveys and questionnaires
KMLabs may invite you to participate in a customer survey. The questionnaires used for these surveys are designed in such a way that the questions can be answered without providing personal information. However, any personal information provided in a questionnaire or survey may be used by KMLabs to improve its products and services.
Generation of anonymized data records
KMLabs may anonymize the personal information covered by this data privacy protection notice to create anonymized data records that can be used to improve KMLabs products and services.
Recording of telephone and chat conversations for the purpose of improving service quality
KMLabs may record telephone or chat conversations for the purpose of improving the quality of its service. The recording process will begin only after you have been informed of it during the conversation.
To keep you informed of new products and services and to collect customer feedback
Within the framework of KMLabs' relationship with you as a customer, KMLabs may keep you informed, to the extent permitted by law, about its products and services (e.g. webinars, seminars and events) that are similar to the products and services from KMLabs that you have already purchased or that you use, or products or services that are directly related. Moreover, KMLabs may contact you to collect feedback regarding products, services, seminars, webinars or events that you have purchased or attended for the purpose of improving the product, service, webinar, seminar, or event in question.
Information on Data Security
KMLabs understands the importance of the protection and discreet handling of the information that you transfer to us via the Internet. Data security on our web pages is a top priority. We have therefore made efforts to ensure that our online security measures are effective. Essential data traffic on KMLabs web pages is therefore encrypted. KMLabs endeavors to update its encryption technology on a continuous basis in line with technical progress in order to guarantee the confidential handling of the information you send us over the Internet.
We use different technologies for authentication, to simplify navigation, and to improve usability. These technologies include “cookies” that measure the use and efficacy of a website. A cookie is a data item that a website sends to your browser. It is stored on your system and is used to identify it (see Cookies, Web Tracking and Web Analytics).
Visitors' IP addresses are captured on our web pages for the analysis of malfunctions, for website administration, and for the attainment of demographic characteristics. Furthermore, we use the IP addresses and other information, made available to us by you on this website or by other means as required, to find out which of our web pages are being visited and what topics interest our visitors.
Cookies, Web Tracking and Web Analytics
KMLabs web pages and online platforms collect and store information, in part in anonymized or pseudonymized form, regarding the surfing behavior of website visitors for the purposes of marketing. This information is stored on your computer using cookies and makes it possible for us to analyze your surfing behavior in anonymous form. This includes, for example, the city you come from, what type of browser and operating system you are using, and which pages you have visited on our website. This information can in no way be used to personally identify you and is used solely for the purpose of improving your browsing experience. To ensure that your information remains anonymous, your IP is either shortened or collected in an anonymous form. Your information is not used for any other purpose, nor is it sent to third parties, without your explicit consent.
Depending on their function and purpose, cookies can be grouped into one of four categories: strictly necessary cookies, performance cookies, functional cookies, and cookies for marketing purposes.
Strictly Necessary Cookies
Strictly necessary cookies are needed to allow you to navigate through a website and use the features built into it. Without these cookies, the website's functionality cannot be guaranteed. This means that certain actions performed by the user (e.g. text input, configuration options) are not stored as the user navigates to other pages on the website.
Functional Cookies
Functional cookies make it possible for a website to store information provided by the user (e.g. username, language selection, current location) to improve their browsing experience and personalize the functionality of the website. For example, a website could provide the user with local pricing information if a cookie is used to store the region that the user is in. Functional cookies are also used to perform commands such as video playback. These cookies collect information in anonymous form and cannot be used to track your use of other web pages.
Performance Cookies
Performance cookies are used to collect information about how a website is used (e.g. information about which pages the visitor visits most frequently and whether or not the user receives any error messages). These cookies do not store any information that could be used to identify the user. The collected information is aggregated and anonymized. These cookies are used exclusively to improve the performance of the website and thus the user's experience.
Cookies for Marketing Purposes
Cookies for marketing purposes are used to present users with advertising or information that is relevant to you and that is tailored to your interests. They are also used to limit the number of impressions of an ad and to measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. They register whether a user has visited a page or not. This information can then be shared with advertisers. Cookies that are used to improve the relevance of advertising are sometimes linked to page features from third parties.
If you want to modify, limit, or object to the use of cookies or the analysis of your surfing behavior, or if you wish to withdraw your objection, you can change and manage the settings for each website in most standard browsers as follows:
Chrome: Click the padlock icon next to the address bar (on SSL-certified pages) or on the information icon (i).
Firefox: Click the icon next to the web address and choose "Options". The cookie management is located under "Privacy & Security".
Internet Explorer: Click the gear icon, then go to "Extras" > "Internet Options". Go to the "Privacy" tab. The cookie management options are located under "Advanced".
How does KMLabs use cookies?
KMLabs uses cookies in a number of ways and for the following purposes:
To authenticate and identify you when you use one of our web pages or applications, so that we can provide you with the services you have requested
To make the KMLabs web pages and applications you use available to you
To store your settings or record the point at which you stopped using a KMLabs web page or application
To measure your use of KMLabs web pages and applications so that these can be improved and modified to fit your interests
To understand what your interests likely are so that we can present you with relevant information when you visit KMLabs web pages
Google Analytics
This website makes partial use of Google Analytics, a web analysis service from Google Inc., headquartered at 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States ("Google"). For this purpose, Google Analytics uses cookies, i.e. text files that are saved on your computer and enable you to analyze your website. As a rule, the information about your use of this website obtained by the cookie is transmitted to a Google server in the USA, where it is saved. However, your IP address will be shortened by Google if IP anonymization is activated on the website. This applies within the EU member states or in other signatory states of the agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transferred to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on the website activities, and to provide the website operator with other services relating to website use and Internet use. Google will not merge other data with the IP address transmitted by your browser within the scope of Google Analytics. You can prevent the saving of cookies by setting your browser software accordingly. However, if you choose to do so, please note that you might not be able to use all the functions of the KMLabs web pages to their full extent. In addition, you may prevent Google's capture and processing of the data generated by the cookie related to your use of web pages (including your IP address) by downloading and installing a browser plugin available via the following link: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de.
Google’s Terms and Conditions of Use and our Data Protection Notice can be found at http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de. and https://policies.google.com/.
Google has added the code "anonymizeIp" to this website to enable the anonymous identification of IP addresses.
Personalized Recommendations
We use software to create user profiles and keep them up to date. The process involves the use of cookies for tracking purposes on the website. Unknown visitors are registered as anonymous.
In some cases, we use retargeting methods by which visitors to our website are tagged so that they can be presented with targeted information on other web pages. This information cannot be used to identify individuals and can be deactivated at any time by changing the display settings or privacy settings in your browser.
In some cases, we use the remarketing feature from Google Inc. This feature is used to present website visitors with advertisements related to their interests within the Google advertising network. To do this, a cookie is saved to the visitor's browser, which makes it possible to identify the user when he or she visits a website that is part of the Google advertising network. On these sites, the user may be presented with advertising related to content that he or she viewed previously on other web pages that employ the Google remarketing feature. According to Google, it does not collect personal information during this process. If you do not want Google to use the remarketing feature, this can generally be deactivated by changing the settings under http://www.google.com/settings/ads.
Through the use of the Google remarketing feature and the "similar audiences" feature, you may be presented with advertising from KMLabs that is tailored to your person and personal interests when you visit web pages within Google's "Display Network". You can also deactivate the cookies used in this process at any time by changing the display settings or privacy settings in your browser.
Using Social Plug-ins
Some KMLabs web pages feature the following social plug-in buttons for other web pages:
These buttons, if displayed on the website, do not establish any contact with the servers from Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter or similar online service providers. For a connection to be activated, and for communication with Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter to be established, you must firstly grant your approval – by clicking on the buttons.
If you are already logged into a social network of your choice, this is carried out without another window being opened. As this transfer occurs directly, we do not obtain any knowledge of the data transferred. What is transferred is the fact that you have launched the respective site. Insofar as you are simultaneously logged onto Facebook or other social media platforms, this information will be assigned to your social media account and will thus be connected to you.
With regard to the further use and storage of your personal data by Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter, please obtain the relevant information directly from these social media companies. It is likewise possible to block social plugins through your browser using add-ons.
Amendments to this Data Protection Notice
This notice is amended occasionally to ensure that it complies with current legal requirements and covers all our online services.
Your legal rights to information, correction, blocking, deletion, and objection are not affected by these changes.
Contacts for Data Protection Requests
For data protection requests, please contact our corporate privacy protection representatives:
KMLabs, Inc.  4775 Walnut Street, Suite 102 Boulder, CO 80301 USA
Contact by email (please do not send confidential or sensitive information): mailto:dataprivacy@KMLabs.com
Contact by phone: +1 303 544 9068 (keyword: "data protection")
Country-Specific Regulations
The following applies to users located in the Russian Federation:
The services mentioned here are not intended for citizens of the Russian Federation whose permanent address is located in Russia. If you are a citizen of the Russian Federation and your permanent address is located in Russia, you acknowledge that any and all personal information you provide when using our services is done so at your own risk and that you are solely responsible for this information; you also acknowledge that by using KMLabs services you grant your explicit permission to have your personal information collected and transferred to the United States and other countries for processing, and that KMLabs cannot be held responsible for failure to adhere to any laws of the Russian Federation.
The following applies to users located in the People's Republic of China:
The services mentioned here are not intended for citizens of the People's Republic of China whose permanent address is located in the People's Republic of China. If you are a citizen of the People's Republic of China and your permanent address is located in the People's Republic of China, you acknowledge that any and all personal information you provide when using our services is done so at your own risk and that you are solely responsible for this information; you also acknowledge that by using KMLabs services you grant your explicit permission to have your personal information collected and transferred to the United States and other countries for processing, and that KMLabs cannot be held responsible for failure to adhere to any laws of the People's Republic of China.
The following applies to users located in the United States:
The content of this Website may be limited for use by persons located within certain geographic regions (including without limitation the United States) and KMLabs makes no claims that the Website or any of its content is accessible or appropriate outside of such regions. Access to the Website may not be legal by certain persons or in certain countries. If you access the Website in contravention of legal restrictions, you do soon your own initiative and are responsible for compliance with local laws.
The "Shine the Light" law of the state of California enables residents of California to request certain information about the data collected by KMLabs and sent to third parties for direct marketing purposes.
If you wish to request additional information covered by the "Shine the Light" law, contact us using the information provided above or submit a request to the address provided with the phrase "California Shine the Light Request" so that we can appropriately categorize your request.
For this process, we require your mailing address, permanent address and an email address so that we can contact you.
